A Guide to the St. Luke's Lutheran Church Records, 1888-1998
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
St. Luke's Lutheran Church Records 1888-1998
Special Collections, Kegley Library
1991.3
17 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the church council of St. Luke's Lutheran Church in 1991.
Historical Information
St. Luke's Lutheran Church, located in the Cove area north of Wytheville on State Route 600, was organized on 1 July 1888 with 52 charter members. The first pastor was Alexander Phillippi.
Scope and Content
This collection includes ledgers, record books, a scrapbook commemorating the 100th anniversary of the church, and an updated cemetery listing.
Contents List
- Church Council Minutes and Baptismal Register. 13 October 1888 - 9 April 1940., 1 volume.
  Church Council minutes, including founding constitution (13 October 1888 - 9 April 1940) p. 1-101; 104. Pages 102-103, 113-116; 125-126; 129-149 are blank. Pages 105-112; 117-124; 127-128 are missing. Baptismal register (1888-1927), p. 150-154; 156-157.
- Luther League Minutes. 1896-1901., 1 item.
  Luther League minutes (3 October 1896 - 3 March 1901) p. 19-97; p. 1-13 lists names of members. Constitution and bylaws, p. 98-99.
- Luther League Minutes. 1905-1911., 1 item.
  Luther League minutes (24 September 1905 - 29 January 1911), p. 7-133; p. 2-4; 134-146 lists names of members.
- Complete Sunday-School Record Book. 1893-1894., 1 item
  The Complete Sunday-School Record Book, (9 April 1893 - 18 March 1894), 64 p.; many pages have been cut and information removed.
- Sunday School Record Books. 1900-1929., 9 items.
  - Sunday School Record Book. April 1900 - December 1902., 75 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1906 - December 1908., 72 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1909 - January 1912., 74 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1912 - December 1914., 80 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1915 - December 1917., 80 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1918 - December 1920., 82 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1921 - December 1923., 80 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1924 - December 1926., 82 p.
  - Sunday School Record Book. January 1927 - June 1929., 60 p.
- Contribution Ledger. April 1921 - December 1923., 1 item.
  Contribution ledger, 19 p.; quarterly summary reports, 8 p. at the end of the volume.
- Account Ledger. 1956-1969., 1 item.
  Account ledger (4 November 1956 - December 1969), p. 1-159; p. 160-177 are blank. Account ledger for individuals, p. 178-190. St. Luke Cemetery Fund, (1 October 1959 - 4 October 1962), p. 191-192.
- St. Luke's Lutheran Church Cemetery, Listing. 1988., 1 item.
  St. Luke's Church Cemetery listing, Cove Area, State Route no. 600), Wythe County, Virginia, 1988, 10 leaves.
- 100th Anniversary Album. 1988., 71 sheets.